# Indra Bayu Sudirman

South Tangerang, Banten | indra.indrabayu@gmail.com | +6289636002345 | LinkedIn | Github | blog.belajarkode.id

### Summary

Dedicated and skilled Software Development Engineer in Test (SDET) with over 2 years of extensive experience in automation testing, CI/CD integration, and test framework development. Proficient in Java, Selenium, Appium, and various CI/CD tools. Committed to ensuring the highest quality of software products through rigorous testing and continuous improvement.

#### **Professional Experiences**

Hijra - QA Automation Freelance

Sept 2024 - Present

Hijra Bank was introduced in 2021 and is owned by Alami Group, a financial technology peer-to-peer (P2P) lending company. Hijra is one of the leading Islamic challenger banks in Southeast Asia, having disbursed more than \$350m to more than 5,000 small businesses in Indonesia. Hijra's key products include sharia-compliant saving and deposit, transactional features, and digital lending, which includes SME and consumer lending.

#### Responsibilities:

- Create & maintain test cases to improve system stability & robustness;
- Collaborate with related product and engineering team in improving tests coverage;
- Collaborate with relevant stakeholders in maintaining a healthy release process;
- Execute end-to-end test before deployment, and smoke test after deployment;
- Response to inquiries from other teams related to issues found in the production environment and help to identify & troubleshoot the issues;
- Stay updated with software testing knowledge and latest advancement in automated testing tools.

#### Tech stack:

Typescript, Playwright, Cypress, Cucumber, Webdriver IO, Appium, Allure Report.

Koinworks - SDET (Software Development Engineer in Test)

May 2022 - August 2024

<u>KoinWorks</u> was established in 2016 as a Peer-to-Peer Lending company. It is an Indonesian Series C-funded (\$108mio raised) fintech company that provides both investment and liability products under a single platform. Today, it's growing to be the first Super Financial App with over 2.5 million active users.

- 2 Million+ Users already onboard towards achieving their business & financial dreams.
- 2,3 Trillion+ Total AUM (Asset Under Management) Koinworks Manages Currently.
- 29 Trillion+ Total Loans Granted Since Started at 2016

#### Responsibilities:

- Writing, execution and monitoring automated test suites using Java, Selenium, Appium, TestNG for IOS, Android, Web and APIs
- Collaborated with QA Manual/QA Testers to define test cases, specifications, and acceptance criteria to ensure software quality.
- Conducted cross-browser and cross-device testing using BrowserStack and LambdaTest to ensure compatibility and performance.
- New tools selection/Research new tools before use by manual QA Team, e.g integration between Testrail and Lambdatest QA Touch.
- Debug failed test cases by analyzing reports, logs and API responses and report bugs with details. Follow-up on bugs to closure.
- Running Regression using CI/CD Pipeline Regularly.

# Tech stack :

Java, Selenium, Appium, RestAssured, TestNG, Gitlab CI/CD, Github Actions

#### **Education**

#### University Indraprasta PGRI, Jakarta

https://unindra.ac.id

July 2016 - August 2020

#### **Skills**

Languages: Java, Javascript, Go, Python, Typescript <sup>1</sup>

Technologies: MySQL, Postgresql, Postman, Selenium, Appium, Maven, TestNG, RestAssured, Nightwatch JS, Grafana k6,

Browserstack, JMeter, Lambdatest, Testrail, CI/CD GitLab, GitHub, GitHub Actions, Playwright, Cucumber, Webdriver IO.

# Certifications

Getting Started with Python Sept 2024

certificate.

Page Object Model pattern for Selenium WebDriver & Java June 2023

certificate.

Scalable web service with Golang May 2022

certificate.

### **Projects**

#### **Automation Framework Koinworks**

**Private Project:** Automation framework for regression testing across Mobile (Android, iOS), Web, and APIs for all Koinworks' apps. Tech Stack: Java, Maven, Selenium, Appium, RestAssured, TestNG, Browserstack, Lambdatest, Testrail, CI/CD GitLab, GitHub Actions.

## **Automation Framework Hijra Bank**

Private Project: Automation framework for end-to-end testing, covering APIs, Web, and databases.

Tech Stack: Typescript, Playwright, Cypress, Cucumber, Webdriver IO, Appium, Allure Report.

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup> The listed languages are my preferred ones, but I am neutral, very interested, and willing to learn other languages.